- [Narrator] The world is unpredictable,
and you never know when yourlife might come under threat.
It pays to be prepared.
But not everyone possessesinbuilt survival instincts.
Can you defeat these 10 riddles
that you must solve to stay alive?
Let's find out.
(gentle music)
Number 10.
Head Above Water.
Imagine you're trapped in a room
and it's slowly filling with water.
You've checked everywhereand there's no way
to turn off the water,or to make an escape.
And you can feel the water level
rising with every passing second.
It's not only the coldness ofthe water making you squeal,
but the knowledge thathelp is five minutes away,
and you only have two minutes or so
until the entire room is flooded.
There's no way you can hold
your breath for three minutes.
You do, however, have astraw, a rope, and a bucket.
And one of them has the power to
buy you time and save your life.
Which item is it?
Be quick.
You only have 10 secondsto come up with a plan.
(drum beats)
Now, maybe you could usethe straw like a snorkel,
but that won't be helpful once
the water reaches the ceiling.
The rope would be useful in so many
other life-or-death situations, but sorry,
it's no good to you right now.
It's actually the bucket that will buy you
a little extra time until help arrives.
Turn it upside-down,put it over your head,
and you'll have an airbubble that will give you
the extra minutes youneed until help arrives.
Number nine.
A Faulty Parachute.
Now, you decide to do a group skydive to
celebrate not drowning, because why not?
As you leap from the plane,
you feel like you're truly flying
and you're more alive than ever.
Not for long, though.
Your bad luck continues andyour parachute doesn't open.
You're plummeting from thesky at an alarming rate.
And as you spin out of control,
you see the hard groundbelow rushing up at you.
How are you going to getout of this predicament?
Are you going to curl intoa ball to protect your
head and your internalorgans from the impact?
Will you put your faithin the reserve parachute?
Or will you try and maneuver to
another skydiver and cling onto them?
Be quick.
You only have 10 seconds until
it's too late to save yourself.
(drum beats)
The answer to your problem is clear.
The reserve parachute is the only
thing guaranteed to save your life.
Curling up into a ballmight minimize damage,
but it also might not.
And as for clinging to another skydiver,
you'll get them killed too.
Number eight.
Paws of Death.
Back on land, you're out for astroll in the great outdoors.
It's a beautiful, sunny day
and you're whistling as you walk.
You're daydreaming aboutwhat you'll have for
lunch once you get back to your campsite.
So much, though, that youdon't notice the huge,
brown bear standing a fewmeters in front of you.
A wave of panic washes over you as the
bear looks into your eyes and growls.
What will you do toescape the paws of death?
Should you stand your groundand try to scare it off?
Maybe you can go the DoctorDolittle route and befriend it.
Should you run away as fast as you can?
Or should you drop tothe ground and play dead?
The bear's approaching.
Make your decision.
(drum beats)
Standing your ground mightwork with a black bear,
as they're much lessterritorial or aggressive.
But a brown bear won't backdown to a tiny human like you.
Running away or befriending a bear
isn't a wise move, no matter the type.
With a brown bear attack, your only option
is to drop to the groundwith your knees to
your chin and your handsprotecting your neck.
When it sees you're not athreat, it will walk away.
Hopefully.
Number seven.
Deadly Venom.
Sadly, your animaltroubles are far from over,
and on another one ofyour eventful strolls,
you get bitten by a venomous snake.
The bite is on your lower leg,
and there's nobody around to help.
What are you going to do toget yourself out of this mess?
You could try to suck the venom
out if you're flexible enough.
Or, maybe it would be better to sit still
and apply a tourniquet to the bitten leg.
Perhaps washing the bitewith clean water and applying
a bandage will help youavoid certain death.
Think fast.
The venom will kill you if
you don't find a way to stop it.
(drum beats)
The first option mightbe tempting if you've
been practicing yoga and are super bendy.
But do you really want venom in your
mouth when it could seep into your
bloodstream from tiny cuts in your gums?
I don't think so.
Washing your wound is no good either.
It won't stop the venomthat's already inside you.
Your only option is to sit still
and keep calm to stop your blood pumping
and to apply a tourniquetto block the venom
from getting into the rest of your body.
Number six.
Professor Evil's Puzzle.
Animals aren't the onlythreat to your life,
as you find out when you'recaptured by Professor Evil.
Luckily, the professor's feeling generous,
and gives you one opportunity to get free.
Don't mess it up.
He gives you three doors to choose from.
Two lead to freedom, butthe other leads to death.
And you can only ask one yes-or-no
question before making your choice.
Professor Evil will answer the question
honestly if you point to a freedom door,
but might lie if youpoint to the death door.
What's your question going to be?
You'd better decide quickly.
Professor Evil isn'tknown for his patience.
(drum beats)
Your only hope is to point to door A,
and ask if door B leads to freedom.
If he says yes, pick door B.
And if the answer is no, choose door C.
Don't get it?
This drawing shows youhow my solution works.
Number five.
Mother Nature's Revenge.
Yes, you've got yourselfinto more trouble.
But this time, it's mothernature that's after you.
You're taking a leisurely drive,
presumably to avoid strolling after
all your trouble with deadly animals.
And you've stopped to...
Relieve yourself in a fieldby the side of the road.
Just then, the weatherturns dark and stormy
and a tornado touchesdown scarily close to you.
There's no shelter.
How are you going toget out of this tangle?
Maybe you could climb a tree and take
shelter under the leafy branches.
Should you find a ditch inthe field and curl up in it?
Or should you make a dashfor your car and hope
that you get to itbefore the tornado does?
Hurry up.
You've got 10 secondsuntil it sweeps you up.
(drum beats)
Climbing a tree wouldn't do you much good.
How are you planning to hangon if the tornado hits it?
Running for your car is too risky.
And even if you make it,the tornado could still
catch you and pick youup, vehicle and all.
Your best option is to get into the ditch
and make yourself as small as possible.
If the tornado passes over you,
it might not be able to liftyou from your hiding place.
Honestly though, it serves you right for
leaving yourself outsidein the first place.
Number four.
Tunnels of Terror.
It's a quiet weekend, so you've decided
to go exploring in a local cave.
Someone with as much bad luck as
you really shouldn't be doing that.
But off you go anyway.
Surprise, surprise.
The worst thing imaginable happens.
There's a landslide andyour exit is blocked.
You manage to find fouralternative tunnels,
but conveniently, they all have signs
telling you whichdangers lurk inside them.
You're going to haveto choose from tunnels
containing molten lavathat will burn you alive,
another huge landslide that will bury you,
poisonous gas that kills all animals,
or thousands of deadly spiders.
Which route will you choose?
Make your decision.
The cave could collapse any second now.
(drum beats)
Three of the tunnels contain things
that will certainly kill humans.
But one of them is onlydangerous to animals.
So long as you're actually a person,
if you select the gas-filled tunnel,
you'll escape unharmed.
Number three.
Red and Blue Pills.
Imagine this.
You're blind, sick, and youhave nobody around to help you.
Poor you.
To stay alive, you have to take
two tablets every single day.
A blue one and a red one.
The pills feel, smell,and taste identical.
So, there's no way ofknowing which is which.
The doctor always puts the pills
in a daily pill box for you.
But one day, you slip and drop the box,
mixing up the two of the days.
Oh, no.
You need to take the pills today and the
doctor can't get to you until tomorrow.
How are you going to figure out which of
the four dropped pills you should take?
(drum beats)
The only way to do it is to break
all four pills into halves.
Then put half of each oneinto two separate piles.
In the end, you'll have twopiles containing four halves,
which guarantees thatyou'll take the right dose.
Number two.
Deadly Inferno.
Oh, no.
You're trapped in another room.
And this time, it's on fire.
How do you get yourselfinto these situations?
The fire is blazingbetween you and the door,
and there's no other wayof escaping the inferno.
Firefighters are on their way,
but you'll need to figure out how
to stay safe until they arrive.
You consider your options.
You could get on the groundand stay as low as possible,
or you could stand on the chair
to get close to the ceiling.
You could take yourclothes off to stay cool,
and possibly give thefirefighters a fright.
Or you could hide under a desk.
Which will you do?
Quick, quick.
The smoke is gettingthicker by the minute.
(drum beats)
Firstly, getting on top ofa chair is a terrible idea.
Smoke and heat both rise,
so you wouldn't stand a chance up there.
Taking your clothes off willexpose your skin to the heat,
which is not what you wantfor your delicate parts.
And getting under a deskwon't really help you much.
Your only choice is to get aslow to the floor as possible,
so you don't suffocate from the smoke,
and just wait until help comes.
Number one.
Four Rooms of Fear.
Congratulations.
You've made it to my final conundrum.
You're condemned to death for
crimes too terrible to speak of,
and your cruel and unusual executioner
gives you the choice between four tanks,
which you'll enter from the top.
And which you'll meet your fate.
The first room contains a vat full
of acid as deep as your chest.
The second is full of blood-thirstymurderers ready to kill.
The third is blazing with raging fires,
and the fourth contains apool full of blood-thirsty
sharks that haven't eaten in six months.
Which horrifying fate do you choose?
(drum beats)
Every room soundsterrifying beyond belief.
But if I was you, I'd go forthe shark-infested waters.
After all, if the sharkshaven't eaten for six months,
they'd all be dead andno danger to you at all.
Congratulations.
You've survived my 10 deadly riddles.
Did you solve them all?
Let me know in the commentsection down below.
And thanks for watching.
(gentle music)
更多精彩，请关注: 漂泊者乐园公众号字幕制作：littleflute